#### RETT A. GRAHAM

(231) 735-6310 | Ann Arbor, MI

rettg@umich.edu | linkedin.com/in/rettg | rettgraham.com

## **OBJECTIVE**

University of Michigan computer science graduate with 2+ years of software development experience through internships, entrepreneurial ventures, and entrepreneurial clubs. I am seeking a software engineer position to apply my problem-solving abilities and passion for innovation.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, University of Michigan

Dean's List | GPA 3.34/4.00

Aug 2020 - Dec 2023

Ann Arbor, MI

Associate of Science and Arts, Northwestern Michigan College

Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society | GPA 3.82/4.00

Aug 2018 - May 2020

Traverse City, MI

### **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages:** Bash | C++ | C | C# | HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Python | SQL | R

Frameworks: Django | Flask | Git | NumPy | OpenCV | Pandas | ReactJS | React Native | SQLite | PyTorch

Cloud Platforms: Amazon Web Services | Firebase

Certificates: Supervised Machine Learning, Stanford University | Python Data Structures, University of Michigan

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **Senior Software Developer Intern**

May 2023 - Aug 2023

Desai Accelerator

Ann Arbor, MI

- Led software development for 6 different tech startup companies and completed 40+ tech projects. A record number of projects resulted in accelerated business timelines of 3+ months.
- Built and designed software that generated social media video ads that reduced the budget toward marketing for the business by around 30%. This software project utilized Bash, ReactJS, and the Remotion framework.
- Attended weekly project management meetings to manage agile development of projects, reducing blockers and increasing team communication, resulting in early completion of some projects by 5+ days.

Cohort Fellow Oct 2022 – Dec 2023

Entrepreneurial Leadership Program

Ann Arbor, MI

- Created business models, market analysis, value propositions, competitive and competitor landscapes, and profit and loss models to evaluate businesses and their needs effectively resulting in 5 established startups in less than 4 months.
- Assisted with tech startup's backend algorithms for college roommate matchmaking, resulting in 98% compatible pairings. These solutions were developed in NextJS, Python, and MongoDB.

Research Assistant Jan 2021 – Jan 2022

NOME Laboratory

Ann Arbor, MI

- Led research and building of image processing software which automated measurement extraction of nuclear material cavity images eliminating the need to manually parse and record 1000+ images. This used Python and OpenCV.
- Held presentations of software research during biweekly meetings with PhD candidates. This resulted in more refined documentation and project quality allowing tasks to be completed 2+ days before deadlines.

# **PROJECTS**

## **Pipeline Processor** – Course Project

 $\mathbf{C}$ 

• Built a five-stage pipeline processor utilizing object-oriented programming. The processor was able to detect data and control hazards showcasing reduced time complexity by 20% compared to a single-cycle and multicycle processor.

# **Sorting Simulator** – *Personal Project*

HTML | CSS | JavaScript

• Implemented 6 core sorting algorithms that visualize elements of an array being sorted in real time. This project strengthened my understanding of core sorting algorithms and local hosting.

## **NBA Game Predictor** – Personal Project

Python | ReactJS

• Developed a game predictor utilizing a logistic regression machine learning model to forecast NBA game outcomes that had a 72% accuracy. Frameworks used were Pandas, Flask, Git, and techniques used were machine learning and APIs.

### **Instagram Clone** – Course Project

### Python | SQL | ReactJS | Amazon Web Services

• Coded a dynamic client-side Instagram clone that mirrored Instagram's core features and algorithms. Frameworks used were Flask and Git and techniques used were APIs.